<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sturgeon on Shannon J. O&#39;Leary</title>
    <link>/tags/sturgeon/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sturgeon on Shannon J. O&#39;Leary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/sturgeon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Genetic diversity and effective size of Atlantic sturgeon, Acipenser oxyrhinchus oxyrhinchus river spawning populations estimated from the microsatellite genotypes of marine-captured juveniles</title>
      <link>/publications/stugeonne/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/stugeonne/</guid>
      <description>Juvenile Atlantic sturgeon (Acipenser oxyrhinchus oxyrhinchus) forming aggregations at coastal sites in the mid-Atlantic Bight were subjected to a mixed stock analysis (MSA) and individual-based assignment using twelve microsatellite loci. We confirmed earlier findings from an analysis of mitochondrial DNA that three river spawning populations (Hudson, James and Delaware Rivers) are the primary sources of these particular marine aggregations. Of the 460 individuals sampled 322, 36 and 47 were assigned to the Hudson, James and Delaware Rivers, respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genetic mixed‐stock analysis of Atlantic sturgeon Acipenser oxyrinchus oxyrinchus in a heavily exploited marine habitat indicates the need for routine genetic monitoring</title>
      <link>/publications/mixedstocksturgeon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/mixedstocksturgeon/</guid>
      <description>Although a previous genetic mixed‐stock analysis (gMSA) conducted in the early 1990s showed that marine‐captured New York Bight Atlantic sturgeon Acipenser oxyrinchus oxyrinchus almost exclusively originated from the Hudson River, fish from southern U.S. rivers were well represented within this contemporary sample (n = 364 fish), at least during the autumn. Widely distributed spawning stocks are therefore exposed to heavy fishing activity and habitat degradation in this relatively small area, illustrating the need for spatial management across multiple management jurisdictions and routine gMSA to account for temporal change.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>