<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Shannon J. O&#39;Leary</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Shannon J. O&#39;Leary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural tags identify nursery origin of a coastal elasmobranch Carcharhinus leucas</title>
      <link>/publications/bullsharksnurseryorigin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/bullsharksnurseryorigin/</guid>
      <description>Traditional methods for evaluating the importance of elasmobranch nursery habitats have focused on estimating densities or abundances of juveniles within individual nurseries; however, rates of juvenile mortality may vary among nurseries. Thus, abundance may not reflect contribution to adult populations, and contribution estimates require methods to identify the nursery origin of adults. We evaluated the use of natural tags, vertebral chemistry (stable isotope analysis, elemental analysis) and genetic markers, to identify bull shark Carcharhinus leucas nursery origin along the Texas coast (northwestern Gulf of Mexico) at multiple spatial scales.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Population Structure of Atlantic Croakers from the Gulf of Mexico: Evaluating a Single‐Stock Hypothesis Using a Genomic Approach</title>
      <link>/publications/croaker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/croaker/</guid>
      <description>The geographic structure of marine fish populations is an important element used in defining stock units, and genetic data have historically been used for this purpose. Here, genetic data were used to elicit population genomic patterns for Atlantic Croakers Micropogonias undulatus collected at five locations in the Gulf of Mexico (hereafter, “Gulf”) and a single location in the southern U.S. Atlantic. Mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA ) haplotypes were used as a baseline for historical lineage delineation and in a comparison with a previous Atlantic Croaker study that was centered on the Atlantic coast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genetic mapping and comparative genomics to inform restoration enhancement and culture of southern flounder, Paralichthys lethostigma</title>
      <link>/publications/sthflounderlinkmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/sthflounderlinkmap/</guid>
      <description>Southern flounder, Paralichthys lethostigma, historically support a substantial fishery along the Atlantic and Gulf coasts of the southern United States. Low year-class strengths over the past few years in the western Gulf of Mexico have raised concern that spawning stocks may be overfished. Current management of the resource includes releasing hatchery-raised juveniles to restock bays and estuaries; additionally, there is a growing interest in the potential for commercial aquaculture of the species.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>These aren’t the loci you’re looking for: Principles of effective SNP filtering for molecular ecologists</title>
      <link>/publications/snpfiltering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/snpfiltering/</guid>
      <description>Sequencing reduced‐representation libraries of restriction site‐associated DNA (RAD seq) to identify single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNP s) is quickly becoming a standard methodology for molecular ecologists. Because of the scale of RAD seq data sets, putative loci cannot be assessed individually, making the process of filtering noise and correctly identifying biologically meaningful signal more difficult. Artefacts introduced during library preparation and/or bioinformatic processing of SNP data can create patterns that are incorrectly interpreted as indicative of population structure or natural selection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Population genetics and geometric morphometrics of the key silverside, Menidia conchorum, a marine fish in a highly-fragmented, inland habitat</title>
      <link>/publications/menconchorum/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/menconchorum/</guid>
      <description>Gene flow between populations is restricted in fragmented habitats, which can promote a more rapid genetic diversification as evolutionary forces act on isolated gene pools. Here, we compare two silverside species occurring in a continuous coastal habitat (tidewater silverside, Menidia peninsulae Goode and Bean, 1879) vs a highly fragmented habitat consisting of hypersaline pools (key silverside, Menidia conchorum Hildebrand and Ginsburg, 1927). First, we aim to better resolve the morphological and genetic relationships between the two nominal species using a haplotype analysis at two loci (NADH dehydrogenase 2, internal transcribed space r2) and geometric morphometrics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genetic Diversity of White Sharks, Carcharodon carcharias, in the Northwest Atlantic and Southern Africa</title>
      <link>/publications/greatwhitesgendiv/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/greatwhitesgendiv/</guid>
      <description>The white shark, Carcharodon carcharias, is both one of the largest apex predators in the world and among the most heavily protected marine fish. Population genetic diversity is in part shaped by recent demographic history and can thus provide information complementary to more traditional population assessments, which are difficult to obtain for white sharks and have at times been controversial. Here, we use the mitochondrial control region and 14 nuclear-encoded microsatellite loci to assess white shark genetic diversity in 2 regions: the Northwest Atlantic (NWA, N = 35) and southern Africa (SA, N = 131).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genetic diversity and effective size of Atlantic sturgeon, Acipenser oxyrhinchus oxyrhinchus river spawning populations estimated from the microsatellite genotypes of marine-captured juveniles</title>
      <link>/publications/stugeonne/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/stugeonne/</guid>
      <description>Juvenile Atlantic sturgeon (Acipenser oxyrhinchus oxyrhinchus) forming aggregations at coastal sites in the mid-Atlantic Bight were subjected to a mixed stock analysis (MSA) and individual-based assignment using twelve microsatellite loci. We confirmed earlier findings from an analysis of mitochondrial DNA that three river spawning populations (Hudson, James and Delaware Rivers) are the primary sources of these particular marine aggregations. Of the 460 individuals sampled 322, 36 and 47 were assigned to the Hudson, James and Delaware Rivers, respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Novel microsatellite loci for white, Carcharodon carcharias and sandtiger sharks, Carcharias taurus (order Lamniformes)</title>
      <link>/publications/greatwhitesmicrosats/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/greatwhitesmicrosats/</guid>
      <description>The white shark, Carcharodon carcharias, and sand tiger shark, Carcharias taurus, are large-bodied lamniform sharks, which are apex predators throughout the temperate zone worldwide. Both species have very low rate of intrinsic population increase and are of conservation concern due to past or present overexploitation. So far only a few microsatellite loci have been developed for population genetics studies on these sharks. Here we present ten novel loci for white sharks and five novel loci for sand tigers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Severe inbreeding and small effective number of breeders in a formerly abundant marine fish</title>
      <link>/publications/wfinbreeding/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/wfinbreeding/</guid>
      <description>In contrast to freshwater fish it is presumed that marine fish are unlikely to spawn with close relatives due to the dilution effect of large breeding populations and their propensity for movement and reproductive mixing. Inbreeding is therefore not typically a focal concern of marine fish management. We measured the effective number of breeders in 6 New York estuaries for winter flounder (Pseudopleuronectes americanus), a formerly abundant fish, using 11 microsatellite markers (6–56 alleles per locus).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Novel microsatellite loci for winter flounder (Pseudopleuronectus americanus)</title>
      <link>/publications/wfmicrosats/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/wfmicrosats/</guid>
      <description>Since the 1980s, heavy exploitation has led to severe population declines in winter flounder, Pseudopleuronectes americanus, a demersal flatfish inhabiting the inshore bays and estuaries of the Northwest Atlantic. Recent studies using a limited number of non-specific microsatellite loci have demonstrated fine-scale population structure. Here, we present 21 novel species-specific microsatellite loci to enhance studies of genetic diversity, population differentiation, effective population size and mating behavior of this important commercial species.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flood pulse effects on benthic invertebrate assemblages in the hypolacustric interstitial zone of Lake Constance</title>
      <link>/publications/benthinvert/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/benthinvert/</guid>
      <description>In contrast to rivers, the effects of water level fluctuations on the biota are severely understudied in lakes. Lake Constance has a naturally pulsing hydrograph with average amplitudes of 1.4 m between winter drought and summer flood seasons (annual flood pulse (AFP)). Additionally, heavy rainstorms in summer have the potential to create short-term summer flood pulses (SFP). The flood pulse concept for lakes predicts that littoral organisms should be adapted to the regularly occurring AFP, ie taking advantage of benefits such as an influx of food sources and low predator pressure, though these organisms will not possess adaptations for the SFP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genetic mixed‐stock analysis of Atlantic sturgeon Acipenser oxyrinchus oxyrinchus in a heavily exploited marine habitat indicates the need for routine genetic monitoring</title>
      <link>/publications/mixedstocksturgeon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/mixedstocksturgeon/</guid>
      <description>Although a previous genetic mixed‐stock analysis (gMSA) conducted in the early 1990s showed that marine‐captured New York Bight Atlantic sturgeon Acipenser oxyrinchus oxyrinchus almost exclusively originated from the Hudson River, fish from southern U.S. rivers were well represented within this contemporary sample (n = 364 fish), at least during the autumn. Widely distributed spawning stocks are therefore exposed to heavy fishing activity and habitat degradation in this relatively small area, illustrating the need for spatial management across multiple management jurisdictions and routine gMSA to account for temporal change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1. Connectivity and local adaptation in marine fishes across their ranges</title>
      <link>/projects/creations/01_popstruct/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/creations/01_popstruct/</guid>
      <description>Current study species include southern flounder, golden tilefish and gafftopsail fish.
Current Projects  Disentangling spatial, environmental, and demographic signals in southern flounder. Range-wide population structure of golden tilefish. Patterns of neutral and adaptive genetic diversity in gafftops sail catfish.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2. Genetic diversity of small populations</title>
      <link>/projects/creations/02_gendivsmallpop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/creations/02_gendivsmallpop/</guid>
      <description>Conservation Genetics focuses on small populations, past study species include white sharks, silversides, sturgeon, and winter flounder, ongoing research includes salmon and bullsharks.
Current Projects  Conservation Genetics of Bullsharks in the northwest Gulf of Mexico Genetic diversity &amp;amp; biocomplexity of chinook salmon  Past Projects  comparison of effective population sizes of white sharks in the Northwest Atlantic and Southern Africa Population genetics and geometric morphometrics of a marine fish in a highly-fragmented, inland habitat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3. Population level effects of a large-scale oil spill on the genetic diversity of demersal fishes</title>
      <link>/projects/creations/03_oilspill/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/creations/03_oilspill/</guid>
      <description>How did the 2010 Deepwater Horizon oilspill affect golden tilefish, and other demersal species?
Current Projects  Effect of the Deepwater Horizon oil spill on the genetic diversity of golden tilefish.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4. DNA Fingerprinting</title>
      <link>/projects/creations/04_dnafingerprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/creations/04_dnafingerprint/</guid>
      <description>DNA fingerprinting can be used to identify individuals and their relationships to each other with a variety of applications, including aquaculture.
Current Projects  Parentage assignment of hatchery offspring Development of sex-specific markers fo aquaculture and restoration purposes  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5. Mixed stock analysis</title>
      <link>/projects/creations/05_mixedstock/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/creations/05_mixedstock/</guid>
      <description>Mixed stock analysis can be used to determine the contribution of individual rivers and estuaries that form the natal habitat and/or nurseries of juveniles recruiting to populations offshore.
Past Projects  Mixed stock analysis of Atlantic sturgeon in Long Island Sound. Baseline assessment for stock assignment of bull sharks along the Texas coast.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6. Genetic Barcoding</title>
      <link>/projects/creations/06_genbarcoding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/creations/06_genbarcoding/</guid>
      <description>Genetic barcoding for species identification &amp;hellip; gut content analaysis, wildlife forensics and other applications.
Past Projects  Gut content analysis of lemon sharks. Wildlife forensics of shark fins. Fisheries characterization in the Caribbean.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search Results</title>
      <link>/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/search/</guid>
      <description>This file exists solely to respond to /search URL with the related search layout template.
No content shown here is rendered, all content is based in the template layouts/page/search.html
Setting a very low sitemap priority will tell search engines this is not important content.
This implementation uses Fusejs, jquery and mark.js
Initial setup Search depends on additional output content type of JSON in config.toml
[outputs] home = [&amp;#34;HTML&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;JSON&amp;#34;] Searching additional fileds To search additional fields defined in front matter, you must add it in 2 places.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>