<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Past and Current Projects on Shannon J. O&#39;Leary</title>
    <link>/projects/creations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Past and Current Projects on Shannon J. O&#39;Leary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/projects/creations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>1. Connectivity and local adaptation in marine fishes across their ranges</title>
      <link>/projects/creations/01_popstruct/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/creations/01_popstruct/</guid>
      <description>Current study species include southern flounder, golden tilefish and gafftopsail fish.
Current Projects  Disentangling spatial, environmental, and demographic signals in southern flounder. Range-wide population structure of golden tilefish. Patterns of neutral and adaptive genetic diversity in gafftops sail catfish.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2. Genetic diversity of small populations</title>
      <link>/projects/creations/02_gendivsmallpop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/creations/02_gendivsmallpop/</guid>
      <description>Conservation Genetics focuses on small populations, past study species include white sharks, silversides, sturgeon, and winter flounder, ongoing research includes salmon and bullsharks.
Current Projects  Conservation Genetics of Bullsharks in the northwest Gulf of Mexico Genetic diversity &amp;amp; biocomplexity of chinook salmon  Past Projects  comparison of effective population sizes of white sharks in the Northwest Atlantic and Southern Africa Population genetics and geometric morphometrics of a marine fish in a highly-fragmented, inland habitat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3. Population level effects of a large-scale oil spill on the genetic diversity of demersal fishes</title>
      <link>/projects/creations/03_oilspill/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/creations/03_oilspill/</guid>
      <description>How did the 2010 Deepwater Horizon oilspill affect golden tilefish, and other demersal species?
Current Projects  Effect of the Deepwater Horizon oil spill on the genetic diversity of golden tilefish.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4. DNA Fingerprinting</title>
      <link>/projects/creations/04_dnafingerprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/creations/04_dnafingerprint/</guid>
      <description>DNA fingerprinting can be used to identify individuals and their relationships to each other with a variety of applications, including aquaculture.
Current Projects  Parentage assignment of hatchery offspring Development of sex-specific markers fo aquaculture and restoration purposes  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5. Mixed stock analysis</title>
      <link>/projects/creations/05_mixedstock/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/creations/05_mixedstock/</guid>
      <description>Mixed stock analysis can be used to determine the contribution of individual rivers and estuaries that form the natal habitat and/or nurseries of juveniles recruiting to populations offshore.
Past Projects  Mixed stock analysis of Atlantic sturgeon in Long Island Sound. Baseline assessment for stock assignment of bull sharks along the Texas coast.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6. Genetic Barcoding</title>
      <link>/projects/creations/06_genbarcoding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/creations/06_genbarcoding/</guid>
      <description>Genetic barcoding for species identification &amp;hellip; gut content analaysis, wildlife forensics and other applications.
Past Projects  Gut content analysis of lemon sharks. Wildlife forensics of shark fins. Fisheries characterization in the Caribbean.  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>